http://www.rajivshah.com/directory/privacy/ftc/

FTC Bars Bogus Anti-Spyware Claims
FTC:
An operation that offered consumers free spyware detection scans that “detected” spyware even if there was not any, to market anti-spyware software that does not work has been barred from making deceptive claims by a U. S. District court at the request of the FTC. The FTC will seek a permanent halt to the marketing scam and redress for consumers.
Posted by rshah on March 19, 2005| Comments (0)
FTC: Dewie keep our data safe?FTC: Dewie keep our data safe?The Federal Trade Commission's new campaign to help consumers keep their personal data safe online includes its very own Internet mascot.Posted by rshah on October 08, 2002| Comments (0)
Microsoft, FTC reach privacy settlementMicrosoft, FTC reach privacy settlementMicrosoft on Thursday agreed to make sweeping changes to its Passport authentication system as part of a settlement agreement with the Federal Trade Commission. The settlement addresses allegations that Passport collects too much information, uses unfair or deceptive practices, and fails to adequately protect the privacy or security of personal information, particularly of children.Posted by rshah on September 11, 2002| Comments (0)
Microsoft puts privacy policy on displayMicrosoft puts privacy policy on displayMicrosoft has begun to incorporate new privacy policies and procedures in upcoming products, apparently in response to this month's settlement with the Federal Trade Commission.Posted by rshah on August 27, 2002| Comments (0)
Federal Trade Commission Runs Web DragnetFederal Trade Commission Runs Web DragnetBut surfing is one of the chief pastimes at the FTC Internet Laboratory. Surfing the Web, that is. Commission attorneys and investigators use the lab to track down online-savvy violators of the 87-year-old Federal Trade Commission Act and related laws.Posted by rshah on April 30, 2002| Comments (0)
Identity Theft, Internet Problems Top Consumer ComplaintsIdentity Theft, Internet Problems Top Consumer ComplaintsIdentity theft was the leading consumer fraud complaint last year, far exceeding gripes about Internet auctions and services. Of the 204,000 complaints compiled by the Federal Trade Commission, 42 percent involved identity theft, the agency said.Posted by rshah on January 24, 2002| Comments (0)
FTC calls Amazon practicesFTC calls Amazon practicesBookseller Amazon and its Alexa Internet subsidiary probably deceived consumers when their Internet software secretly passed on personal information to the company, the Federal Trade Commission said. But the FTC said it will not take any action against the online bookseller because one of the software programs in question, zBubbles,is no longer operational and Alexa has changed its stated privacy policy, see also SlashdotPosted by rshah on June 01, 2001| Comments (0)
FTC Settles With Sites That Broke Child Privacy LawFTC Settles With Sites That Broke Child Privacy LawThe Federal Trade Commission is celebrating the first anniversary of a law designed to protect children's privacy by cracking down on three companies that collected information about minors without parental consent. The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), which went into effect April 21, 2000, requires sites that collect information from children to get parental permission first--sometimes via phone, mail or fax.Posted by rshah on April 20, 2001| Comments (0)
Mobile Wireless Web, Data Services and Beyond: Emerging Technologies and Consumer IssuesMobile Wireless Web, Data Services and Beyond: Emerging Technologies and Consumer IssuesHearing at the FTC, December 11-12, 2000 that examined emerging wireless Internet and data technologies and the privacy, security, and consumer protection issues they raise.Posted by rshah on February 07, 2001| Comments (0)
FTC drops probe into DoubleClick privacy practicesFTC drops probe into DoubleClick privacy practicesThe Federal Trade Commission said Monday that it has closed its investigation of the data-collection practices of online advertising network DoubleClick, saying the company has not violated its privacy policy.Posted by rshah on January 23, 2001| Comments (0)
FTC Tackles Wireless RegulationFTC Tackles Wireless RegulationAdvocates gathered at a Federal Trade Commission workshop on Tuesday to recommend more federal regulations directed at the growing wireless content industry.Posted by rshah on December 14, 2000| Comments (0)
DoubleClick tracks porn sitesDoubleClick tracks porn sitesSee also Slashdot and replies from DoubleClick and iFriendsPosted by rshah on July 05, 2000| Comments (0)
FTC Seeks Authority to Regulate Online PrivacyFTC Seeks Authority to Regulate Online Privacyin May 2000Posted by rshah on June 24, 2000| Comments (0)
New FTC Panel Will Be Web Privacy WatchdogNew FTC Panel Will Be Web Privacy WatchdogPosted by rshah on June 24, 2000| Comments (0)
Data ProfilingData ProfilingPosted by rshah on June 24, 2000| Comments (0)
Syndicate this site (XML)
